<Document>
# Important Character Creation Tips
This is a guide for the parts of character creation that affect gameplay.

[textlink="The guide for cosmetic customization can be found here." link="YourFirstCharacter"]

## Spawn Priority
This affects where you spawn when you join a round after it has started.

Choosing "Arrivals" will have you spawn on a separate arrivals station where you'll wait for a shuttle to arrive and take you to the main station.

Choosing "Cryosleep" will have you wake up in a cryopod already on station.

If you choose "None", the game will either pick for you or choose the only spawn available for the current station.

This is mostly an arbitrary choice. You can safely leave it as "None" and not experience any real inconvenience.

## Jobs
You can set your job preferences in the lobby. Getting a job is [color=#a4885c]not guaranteed[/color], as spots will be randomly distributed among all interested players at round start.
You have a chance to get picked for high priority first, then medium priority, then low priority.
You're also given the option to auto-join as a passenger, or return to lobby if you don't get any of your preferred jobs.

Some jobs are locked until you play enough time on other, starter jobs.

[textlink="For more information on jobs, click here." link="Jobs"]

## Job Loadouts
You can also select [color=#a4885c]loadouts[/color] for each job. Loadouts are clothing items and trinkets that you spawn with when you join the game. Some items are locked behind play time.
This can affect gameplay in different ways, as some clothing items have [color=#a4885c]armor[/color] or [color=#a4885c]slow down your movement speed[/color]. This particularly affects command staff and security officers.

You can also choose which bag you spawn with.
[color=#a4885c]Backpacks[/color] are average size and make it easier to carry large items. [color=#a4885c]Satchels[/color] have more space than backpacks, but large items may not fit. [color=#a4885c]Duffel bags[/color] are large, but slow you down.

## Antagonists
Opting in to be an [color=#a4885c]antagonist[/color] puts you in the pool of potential antagonists for the round, and you may be selected to be one at round start. This doesn't guarantee you'll become one, so don't use this as an excuse to self-antag!
Like job priorities, multiple players will be randomly selected from the eligible and willing pool. If you're a command member or security officer, you won't become an antagonist.

[textlink="For more information on antagonists, click here." link="Antagonists"]

Joining multiple rounds, or going ghost/disconnecting/suiciding after not being selected as an antag is considered antag-rolling (or role-hunting) and goes against the rules.
Many people patiently wait their turn to be antagonists, so [color=#a4885c]we ask that you refrain from opting into antagonist roles if you're not ready for them[/color].

## Traits
Speech traits change your speech. Sometimes heavily.

These include:
- No accent (turns off the accent from your chosen species)
- Cowboy accent (word replacement, partner)
- Frontal lisp ("s" becomes "th")
- Italian accent (Mamma-mia, word replacement)
- Pathological liar (word replacement, replaces words like "yes" with "no")
- Pirate accent (Argh, word replacement)
- Social anxiety (st-st-stuttering)
- Southern US dialect (replaces "-ing" with "-in'" and similar)

You should be comfortable with normal speech or with a light accent like social anxiety or southern accent before taking on heavy accents like Italian or Cowboy.

There are also restriction traits. Before taking one, familiarize yourself with the gameplay, as some of these will be difficult for newer players.

They include:
- Blindness (severely limits your vision)
- Lightweight drunk (you get drunk faster and suffer more from alcohol's negative effects)
- Mute (you can't speak or whisper, but can communicate via emotes, pen and paper)
- Narcolepsy (you randomly fall asleep at unpredictable and often inconvenient times)
- Pacifist (you can't harm, shoot, or throw sharp things at people)
- Paracusia (you occasionally hear sounds that weren't real)
- Nearsighted (somewhat limits your vision without glasses)
- Snoring (you make loud snoring sounds while sleeping)
- Unrevivable (you cannot be resuscitated after your untimely demise)
</Document>
