<Document>
# Speech and Text Channels
Communication is a key part of Space Station 14. You can press [keybind="FocusChatInputWindow"/] to focus the chat input box.

The word next to the text input box is the [color=#a4885c]text channel[/color] you're going to send the message to, or rather, how exactly you're going to say what you type.

Say is normal speech at normal volume.

Whisper can only be heard when someone is close by. You automatically whisper into your headset to send a message.

Emotes are gestures you make. They can be seen by everyone who isn't blinded. You'll often see mimes doing lots of emotes.

You can send a whisper by starting a message with [color=#a4885c][keybind="FocusWhisperChatWindow"/][/color], and emotes can be sent by starting a message with [color=#a4885c]@[/color].
You can also cycle through all these text channels by pressing [keybind="CycleChatChannelForward"/].

People may not catch everything you say if you stand too far away from them. This is especially important if you whisper.

## Headset

Your headset allows you to communicate across the station and with your specific [color=#a4885c]department[/color].

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetGrey"/>
</Box>

To send a [color=#a4885c]common message[/color] over the headset, use the [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] channel by starting your text with a [color=#32cd32]semicolon (;)[/color].
People standing right next to you may pick up parts of your radio message even if they don't have access to the relevant radio channel. Watch out for eavesdroppers.

## Department Headset

You can send messages over your department's channels using a [color=#32cd32]colon (:)[/color] followed by a department letter if you're wearing a headset with your department's encryption key.

Examine your headset to see available department channels for you.

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ClothingHeadsetEngineering"/>
</Box>

Examining an unmodified engineering headset will show you the prefixes for [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] and [color=#f37746]Engineering[/color] channels.

You can also use [color=#a4885c]:h[/color]. This hotkey will automatically switch to your department's channel.
For example, if you're a station engineer, [color=#a4885c]:h[/color] will switch to [color=#f37746]:e[/color].

## Encryption Keys
[color=#a4885c]Encryption keys[/color] grant you access to the corresponding channel.
  
Examining our engineering headset from the previous example shows us [color=#32cd32]Common[/color] and [color=#f37746]Engineering[/color] channels because the engineer's headset starts the shift with those [color=#a4885c]encryption keys[/color].
  
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyCommon"/>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="EncryptionKeyEngineering"/>
</Box>
  
You can remove encryption keys by using a [color=#a4885c]screwdriver[/color] on the headset. New encryption keys are inserted into the headset by clicking on it with an encryption key in hand.

All command staff have spare encryption keys, but you can also request one at the HoP's office when changing jobs.

## OOC Channels
OOC (out of character) channels exist outside the game world. These include LOOC, OOC, and dead chat.

LOOC is enabled during the round, OOC is usually disabled until the round ends, and you can only see and talk in dead chat when you're... well... dead.

Don't discuss the current round in Discord or OOC if it's enabled during the round.
</Document>
